<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Principles of HitchDev on HitchDev</title>
    <link>https://hitchdev.com/principles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Principles of HitchDev on HitchDev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://hitchdev.com/principles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Commit messages and their meanings</title>
      <link>https://hitchdev.com/principles/commits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hitchdev.com/principles/commits/</guid>
      <description>Each commit message in hitchdev projects takes the form TYPE : Message.
BUGFIX Bugfix on implemented feature that does not intentionally impact pre-existing defined behavior. Should typically come with a story or change to a story that invokes the behavior that failed before the bug was fixed.
FEATURE Newly implemented feature that does not intentionally impact pre-existing defined behavior. Should come accompanied with a story or change to a story that invokes and describes the behavior.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extreme dogfooding</title>
      <link>https://hitchdev.com/principles/extreme-dogfooding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hitchdev.com/principles/extreme-dogfooding/</guid>
      <description>All of the libraries on this website are the result of extreme dogfooding.
The idea behind this principle is that not only are the libraries used in anger in real life production code, but that also:
 The libraries&amp;rsquo; design (and even the idea itself) emerged from heavy refactoring rather than out of the blue. The libraries are built and trialed in real life situations to eliminate most of the bugs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HitchDev Principles</title>
      <link>https://hitchdev.com/principles/hitchdev/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hitchdev.com/principles/hitchdev/</guid>
      <description>The HitchDev framework is committed to the following principles:
 Automated consistent dev and test environment setup - there should be fewer than 5 steps to get the average dev or test environment set up. Executable specifications should define the behavior of projects only - where this becomes cumbersome, it&amp;rsquo;s a sign that the project should be broken into subprojects. The specifications should be terse and strongly typed. The projects should be tested against a realistic a model of the real world they will face as possible.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>